<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Raspberry-Pi - Tag - Ittosei Blog</title>
        <link>http://ittosei.com/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
        <description>Raspberry-Pi - Tag - Ittosei Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:02:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ittosei.com/tags/raspberry-pi/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Simple Bash Script for Monitoring Raspberry Pi Temperature</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-temp/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:02:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-temp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The following script will monitor Raspberry Pi temperature.
#!/bin/bash while [ : ] do command=`/opt/vc/bin/vcgencmd measure_temp` echo $command sleep 3 done The script will print the temperature every 3 seconds.
You can run vcgencmd measure_temp for one temperature check.
Change sleep 3 to other number for different intervals.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Security Cam From Scratch: Setting Up Hardware and Software [Part 2]</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-secruity-cam-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 17:26:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-secruity-cam-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Setting up Pi There are already many guide for this. I will briefly introduce the procedure here. Please look for other guide for troubleshooting.
Go to the official website to download the Raspbian OS. You will download an imager burner. Connect your Pi to your PC via usb. Flash the image to your Pi. If you are doing headless setup. You will need to enable SSH in a config file. Please refer to other guide.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Security Cam From Scratch: Motivation and Hardwares [Part 1]</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 22:06:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I wanted a security camera for a while. There are many reasons that I am insist building it. Of course, the primary reason is for fun. If you are looking for a complete product, there are some open source pi security projects built already. For example, the MotionEyeOS. I personally have not installed it, but you can check out the YouTube for other people&rsquo;s review. I want my Pi run other tasks whiling serving as a security camera.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Camera Module Documentation</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-cam-doc/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 11:33:09 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-cam-doc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An archive of Raspberry Pi camera module documentation]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
