<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Ittosei Blog</title>
        <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Ittosei Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 21:01:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ittosei.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Security Cam From Scratch: Sending and Receiving Videos [Part 3]</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-3/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 21:01:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post will cover the basic function of the project, sending and receiving videos.
I choose the official API for camera sending usage. My site also have a copy with a table of content that helps you navigate the content. It is a higher level implementation of OpenMAX. There is also a Python library for Pi camera that you can use.
Save Video Locally Run raspivid --timeout 0 --bitrate 800000 --segment 10000 -v -a 4 -a %Y-%m-%d-%X --output video_%c.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Simple Bash Script for Monitoring Raspberry Pi Temperature</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-temp/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 16:02:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-temp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The following script will monitor Raspberry Pi temperature.
#!/bin/bash while [ : ] do command=`/opt/vc/bin/vcgencmd measure_temp` echo $command sleep 3 done The script will print the temperature every 3 seconds.
You can run vcgencmd measure_temp for one temperature check.
Change sleep 3 to other number for different intervals.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Security Cam From Scratch: Setting Up Hardware and Software [Part 2]</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 17:26:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Setting up Pi There are already many guide for this. I will briefly introduce the procedure here. Please look for other guide for troubleshooting.
Go to the official website to download the Raspbian OS. You will download an imager burner. Connect your Pi to your PC via usb. Flash the image to your Pi. If you are doing headless setup. You will need to enable SSH in a config file. Please refer to other guide.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Security Cam From Scratch: Motivation and Hardwares [Part 1]</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 22:06:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-security-cam-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I wanted a security camera for a while. There are many reasons that I am insist building it. Of course, the primary reason is for fun. If you are looking for a complete product, there are some open source pi security projects built already. For example, the MotionEyeOS. I personally have not installed it, but you can check out the YouTube for other people&rsquo;s review. I want my Pi run other tasks whiling serving as a security camera.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Forum Framework Recommendation: Discourse</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/discourse/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 05:17:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/discourse/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Discourse is an open source forum framework. I found it is used in the forum I visited. I did an installation on the $5 Digital Ocean Droplet. Then I realize a lot of forums are using it by recognizing its optional styles.
The official website is here. At first glance, the website does not mention self-hosting options. But in the &ldquo;about&rdquo; page, you will find the Github repository.
Note on Digital Ocean Droplet The installation is extremely easy.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Amethyst Shortcuts - MacOS Tiling Window Management</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/amethyst/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 03:37:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/amethyst/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I was very satisfied about the productivity of i3wm under Linux. Amethyst is the replacement that I found under MacOS. I list the default shortcuts with some organizations for getting used to it.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>First Moon Observation</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/first-observation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 16:36:52 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/first-observation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/first-astro/title.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Recently, I purchased my first telescope. Soon I conducted my first observing session in my backyard. It was full moon, but the view condition isn&rsquo;t that perfect. The view though telescope is wonderful, but not as astonishing as I imagined. I took some pictures though telescope by my phone. It is not perfectly but I still love it.
Images I cropped the image for file sizing.
9mm" 9mm  30mm" 30mm  Overall, I was very exciting during the whole observation.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Manjaro I3 Shortcut Cheatsheet</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/i3-help/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 10:43:18 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/i3-help/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Note  This is a cheatsheet that came along with the installation of Manjaro i3wm. I ported the PDF version to this Markdown format.
From the signature, the original author is oberon.
It is tedious for me to open helper PDF every time and resize it to my preference.
I hope this will help you navigating in the i3.
   Welcome to manjaro i3! The default mod-key is &lt;Super&gt; (Windows-key).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Raspberry Pi Camera Module Documentation</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-cam-doc/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 11:33:09 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pi-cam-doc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An archive of Raspberry Pi camera module documentation]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Setting Up Wireguard VPN in Raspberry Pi</title>
    <link>http://ittosei.com/posts/pivpn/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 01:40:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://ittosei.com/posts/pivpn/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>This tutorial will help you setting up a Wireguard VPN on Raspberry Pi by using PiVPN installer. This article will use Raspberry Pi OS (Raspbian) for installation. The <a href="https://www.pivpn.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">PiVPN</a> site claims the installer will also work on Debian and Ubuntu.</p>
<p>I choose <strong>Wireguard</strong> over <strong>OpenVPN</strong> due to the convenience of connecting though QR code. In <strong>OpenVPN</strong>, you have to transfer security key via USB stick and some extra works to transfer it to a phone. However <strong>OpenVPN</strong> has the option with more encryption bits, but more encryption bits will cost more to compute and slow the transfer time. You can find out more in the <a href="https://www.pivpn.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">PiVPN</a> website.</p>
<p>I assume my audience have little background knowledge, so hope you can follow this without any problem. <strong>But I do not assume that you know how to type in the terminal.</strong></p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
